Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Vertical Files: Subjects ALBA.VF.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Vertical Files: Subjects
1930-2011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives
Tamiment Library
ALBA.VF.001
6.5 Linear Feet in 9 boxes
The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Vertical Files are a rich source for background information on the people, events and topics related to the ALBA collections in the Tamiment Library and include coverage of the International Brigades as well. The files contain a variety of documents such as newspaper clippings, flyers, brochures, biographical material, anniversary and exhibit programs, obituaries, and other items. Consult the folder list in this collection to find material on specific events or topics. See the ALBA Vertical File on Individuals to find biographical material on specific individuals.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of files of printed ephemera such as broadsides, brochures, bulletins, catalogs, clippings, flyers, leaflets, manifestoes, pamphlets, press releases, reports, reprints and other documents relating to a broad range of subjects connected with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.
Provenance
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with organizations and bookstores, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series: Series I: ALBA Subject Files. Folders in boxes 1-8 are arranged alphabetically; folders in other boxes are arranged in the order in which they were created.
Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x African Americans.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- International brigades.; Pamphlets.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, British.; Printed ephemera.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Prisoners and prisons.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Irish.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Veterans.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Refugees.; Spain - History - Civil War, 1936-1939 - Participation, Czech; Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Brochures.; Press releases.; Bulletins.; Programs (documents).; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Jewish.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Articles.; Reports.; Broadsides (notices); Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
- Series I: ALBA Subject Files, 1; 470732
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) (I), 471283 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) (II), 471282 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ALBA News: Newsletter, Brandeis University, 471281 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ALBA Report: Newsletter, Brandeis University, 471280 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Elizabeth Compa Essay, 471279 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: General, 471278 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: New Masses Articles, 471277 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Photographs, General, 471276 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Activists Forever! Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 471275 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African-American Volunteers, 471274 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - African-American Volunteers: "The Good Fight" (Christopher T. Brooks), 471273 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aid to the Republic: U.S. Organizations, 471272 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Aide Enfantine d'Arriere-Garde (Oversize), 471271 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 1)
  - Albacete, 471270 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albanian Volunteers, 471269 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ambulance Drivers, 471268 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Committee for a Free Spanish Republic, 471267 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Committee for Spanish Freedom, 471266 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy, 471265 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American League against War and Fascism, 471264 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Relief Ship for Spain, 471263 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Rescue Ship Mission, 471262 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Society for Technical Aid to Spanish Democracy, 471261 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Student Union, 471260 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Amicale des anciens interas du Camp du Vernet d'Ariege, 471259 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Amicale des Anciens Volontaires Francais en Espagne Republicaine et des Amis du Peuple Espagnol, 471258 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Anarchist Exiles in France, 471257 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Anarchists: General, 471256 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Anarchists (US), 471255 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Anniversary, 10th, 471254 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Anniversary, 14th, 471253 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Anniversary, 15th, 471252 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Anniversary, 20th, 471251 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Anniversary, 21st, 471250 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Anniversary, 22nd, 471249 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Anniversary, 25th, 471248 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Anniversary, 25th (Oversize), 471247 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary, 30th, 471246 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Anniversary, 32nd, 471245 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Anniversary, 34th, 471244 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Anniversary, 35th, 471243 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Anniversary, 36th, 471242 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Anniversary, 37th, 471241 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Anniversary, 39th, 471240 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Anniversary, 40th, 471239 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Anniversary, 41st, 471238 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Anniversary, 42nd, 471237 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Anniversary, 43rd, 471236 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Anniversary, 44th, 471235 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Anniversary, 45th, 471234 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Anniversary, 46th, 471233 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Anniversary, 47th, 471232 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Anniversary, 48th, 471231 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Anniversary, 50th, 471230 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Anniversary, 50th Booklet, 471229 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Anniversary, 51st, 471228 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Anniversary, 52nd, 471227 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Anniversary, 53rd, 471226 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Anniversary, 54th, 471225 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Anniversary, 55th, 471224 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Anniversary, 56th, 471223 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Anniversary, 57th, 471222 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Anniversary, 58th, 471221 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Anniversary, 60th, 471220 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Anniversary, 60th: Proclamations (Oversize), 471219 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary, 61st, 471218 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Anniversary, 64th, 471217 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Anniversary, 65th, 471216 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Anniversary, 66th, 471215 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Anniversary, 70th, 471214 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Anniversary, 71st, 471213 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Anniversary, 73rd, 471212 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Anniversary, 76th, 471211 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Anti-Nazi Propaganda, 471210 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Archives: U.S. and Britain, 471209 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Archivo de las Brigadas Internacionales, Madrid, 471208 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Argentinean Volunteers, 471207 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Armenian-American Volunteers, 471206 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Artists (in Abraham Lincoln Brigade), 471205 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Asian Volunteers, 471204 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Asociacin de Amigos de las Brigadas Internacionales, 471203 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Asociacin de Descendientes del Exilio Espaol, 471202 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Asociacion de Ex-Presos y Represaliados Politicos, 471201 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Attorney General's List, 471200 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Australian Volunteers, 471199 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Austrian Volunteers, 471198 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Aviation: G. Hall Roosevelt, 471197 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Aviators: Condor Legion, 471196 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Aviators: General, 471195 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Aviators: Soviet (Paul Whelam File), 471194 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Aviators: Spanish, 471193 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Aviators: US, 471192 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers, Local 87, 471191 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Banners and Flags, 471190 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Barcelona, 471189 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Battlefield Tourism (Nationalist): S. Holguin Article, 471188 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Belchite, 471187 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Belgian Volunteers, 471186 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Belgian Volunteers: Award to VALB (Oversize), 471185 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 4)
  - Benicassim (Hospital), 471184 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Books: Spanish Civil War, 471183 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Botvin Committee to Aid Jewish Volunteers in Spain, 471182 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Botwin Company (see also Jews in the Spanish Civil War), 471181 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brandeis University: Spanish Civil War Collections, 471180 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Bremen: Nazi Flag Incident, 471179 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - British Volunteers: 60th Anniversary/War Memorial, 471178 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - British Volunteers: Ambulance Drivers, 471177 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - British Volunteers: Archives, 471176 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - British Volunteers: General, 471175 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - British Volunteers: Hull, England, 471174 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - British Volunteers: Individuals, 471173 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Brooklyn Volunteers, 471172 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Brookwood Labor College Graduates in the Spanish Civil War, 471171 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Browden Brigade, 471170 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Brownsville, 471169 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Brunete, 471168 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bulgarian Volunteers, 471167 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - California Volunteers, 471166 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Camp Wo-Chi-Ca, 471165 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Canadian Committee for a Democratic Spain, The (! Amnistia !), 471164 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Canadian Participation: Aid, 471163 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Canadian Participation: Archives, 471162 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Canadian Participation: Myron Momryck Correspondence, 471161 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Canadian Volunteers, 471160 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Canadian Volunteers: Hungarians, 471159 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Canadian Volunteers: Jewish, 471158 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Canadian Volunteers: Ukrainians, 471157 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Carmen: Spanish Civil War Inspired Production, 471156 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Catalonia, 471155 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War, 471154 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War (Oversize), 471153 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 5)
  - Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War: Fr. Michael O'Flan... Catholics and the War in Spain", 471152 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Cemetery of Fuencarral (Madrid), 471151 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Centre d'Estudis d'Historia Contempornia (Barcelona), 471150 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Chicago Friends of the Lincoln Brigade, 471149 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Chicago Volunteers, 471148 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Children, Aid to, 471147 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Children: Exiles in the USSR, 471146 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Children's Drawings, 471145 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Children's Homes/Schools, 471144 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Chinese Participation, 471143 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Christian Advocate Coverage (Methodist Episcopal Church South) (Oversize), 471142 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 6)
  - City College Volunteers, 471141 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - City College New York (CCNY)/Baruch College: Volunteers in Lincoln Battalion, Exhibit, 471140 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - City College Volunteers-in-Spain Memorial Scholarship Committee, 471139 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Colorado Volunteers, 471138 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Columbia University, 471137 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Columbia University: Guide to Spanish Refugee Relief Organizations, 471136 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Columbia University Volunteers, 471135 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Comite Antifacista Espanol (Brooklyn, NY), 471134 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Commissars, 471133 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Committee for a Democratic Spain, 471132 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Communist Party of Spain (PCE), 471131 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Communist Party, USA: California, Aid to Spain, 471130 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Confederacion Nacional de Trabajo (CNT), 471129 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Conference: 50th Anniversary (University of Southampton, 1986), 471128 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Conference: 50th Anniversary Commemorative Week (Queens College, CUNY, 1986), 471127 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conference: 70th Anniversary (Paris, 2006), 471126 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conference: 70th Anniversary (University of Salamanca, 2006), 471125 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Conference: "Americans in Spain, The International Brigade: R...lling the Story" (Chicago, 1999), 471124 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conference: "Continuing History of the Spanish Civil War" (NYU, 2007), 471123 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Conference: "Documenting Displacement: Images of Spanish Civil War Refugees" (NYU, 2009), 471122 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Conference: France, January 1939, 471121 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Conference: International Conference on the Spanish Civil War (Barcelona, 1979), 471120 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Conference: Lausanne, Switzerland, 471119 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Conference: Madison, WI, December 2006, 471118 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Conference: Madrid 2006, 471117 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conference: Smithsonian Institution, 471116 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Conference: "Spain 1936-1976" (Bethune College, York University), 471115 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conference: "The Spanish Civil War Fifty Years After" (Penn State University, 1986), 471114 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Conference: "The Spanish Civil War, Thirty Years Later (Harvard-M.I.T., 1969), 471113 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Conference: "War without Limits: Spain, 1936-39 and Beyond" (University of Bristol, U.K.), 471112 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Coordinating Committee to Lift the Spanish Embargo, 1938-1939, 471111 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Croatian Participation, 471110 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cuban Volunteers, 471109 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Currency, 471108 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Curriculum Projects, 471107 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cypriot Volunteers, 471106 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Czechoslovak Volunteers, 471105 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names and Biographical Information, 1975; 585764 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Scope and Content Note
    Compact disc of 641-page document in Czech from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives with names and biographical information for 2,329 volunteers.
  - Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - Introduction through page 315, 1975; 585763 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - page 316-641, 1975; 585765 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - page 642-679 (index of names), 1975; 585766 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Contents are not entirely in alphabetical order.
  - Daily Worker Coverage, 471104 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Daily Worker Coverage (Oversize), 471103 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 7)
  - Debs Battalion/Debs Column, 471102 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Department Store Workers' Union, 471101 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Deserters, 471100 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dissertations and Research Papers (Lists), 471099 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Division Hispana del Voto Independiente, La, 471098 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Ebro, Battle of, 471097 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - El Salvador, 471096 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Executions, 471095 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Exhibits: "Antifascistas, British and Irish Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War" (IBMT), 471094 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Exhibits: "Aura of the Cause", 471093 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Exhibits: "Brigadistas and Refugees: Crossing Borders with Ca... Mexico Suitcase" (NYC, May 2009, 471092 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Exhibits: Chicago, 471091 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Exhibits: Delphic Studios, NYC, 1937, 471090 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Exhibits: "Dreams and Nightmares": Imperial War Museum, 471089 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Exhibits: "Facing Fascism: New York and the Spanish Civil War", 471088 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Exhibits: General, 471087 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Exhibits: "Imagenes Recuperadas", 471086 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Exhibits: Italy, Spanish Civil War Exhibits, 471085 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Exhibits: "Lincoln Brigade in Aragon", 471084 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Exhibits: "No Jubilem la Memoria!" (Les Masies, Spain), 471083 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Exhibits: "No Pasarn" (Jerusalem), 471082 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Exhibits: "Posters from the Spanish Civil War" (NYU, 2008), 471081 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Exhibits: "Posters of the Spanish Civil War" (NYC, 1991), 471080 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Exhibits: "Shouts from the Wall" (I), 471079 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Exhibits: "Shouts from the Wall" (II), 471078 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Exhibits: "The Spirit Lives: Photos from the Spanish Civil War" (1998), 471077 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Exhibits: "They Still Draw Pictures", 471076 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Exhibits: University of California Berkeley, 1986, 471075 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Exhibits: "Voices of the Other America," Prospectus, 471074 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Exiles, 471073 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Exiles: France, 471072 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Exiles: France (Oversize), 471071 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 8)
  - Federacio Nacional de Pioneros de Catalunya, 471070 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Fight against War and Fascism (periodical), 471069 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Figurine: El mes petit de tots, 471068 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Film: "American Commander in Spain", 471067 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Film: "Canadienses, Los", 471066 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Film: "Chronicles of Hope: the International Brigades in Spain", 471065 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Film: "Defenders of the Faith", 471064 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Film: "Extranjeros de se Mismos", 471063 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Film: "Forever Activists", 471062 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Film: "Good Fight": General, 471061 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Film: "Good Fight": NEH Grant Application, 471060 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Film: "Good Fight": Proposal and Funding, 471059 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Film: "Good Fight": Reviews, 471058 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Film: "Heart of Spain", 471057 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Film: "In Search of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade", 471056 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Film: "Into the Fire", 471055 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Film: "Land and Freedom", 471054 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Film: "Madrid before Hanita", 471053 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Film: "Ninos de Russia", 471052 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Film: "Shouts from the Wall: Voices of the Spanish Civil War", 471051 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Film: "Sierra de Teruel", 471050 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Film: "Silencio Roto", 471049 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Film: "Spain in Exile" (1946), 471048 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Film: "Spain in Flames", 471047 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 21)
  - Film: Spanish Civil War (U.K. Newsreels), 471046 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Film: "Spanish Earth", 471045 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Film: "To Die in Spain", 471044 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Film: "A Valley in Spain", 471043 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Film: "Vieja Memoria" (Jaime Camino), 471042 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Film: "With the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in Spain" (Cartier-Bresson), 471041 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Films: Spanish Civil War, General, and Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 471040 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Finnish and Finnish-American Volunteers (I), 471039 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Finnish and Finnish-American Volunteers (II), 471038 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Folkways, 471037 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Fondation Internationale d'Etudes Historiques et Sociales, 471036 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Franco and Franco Regime, 471035 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Franco and Franco Regime (Oversize), 471034 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 9)
  - Franco, Volunteers for, 471033 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - French Volunteers, 471032 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 471031 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Oversize), 471030 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 10)
  - Friends of the American Lincoln Brigade, Boston Branch, 471029 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 11)
  - Friends of Spain (London, England), 471028 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Friends of the Lincoln Battalion: Morningside Branch (1937), 471027 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Friends of the Spanish Republic, 471026 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - German Democratic Republic, 471025 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - German Volunteers, 471024 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Glasgow Volunteers, 471023 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Graves: International Brigades, 471022 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Greater Boston Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 471021 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Greek Volunteers, 471020 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Greek-American Volunteers, 471019 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Grupo Sacco y Vanzetti (International Brigade Unit), 471018 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Grupo Tierra Y Libertad, 471017 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Guernica, 471016 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Guernica Anniversary: Italy, 471015 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Guernica: Exhibited at Valentine Gallery, NYC, 1937, 471014 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Guernica: Peace Museum, 471013 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Guerrilla Warfare, 471012 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Harvard University: Widener Library, 471011 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Harvard/Radcliffe Student Unions, 471010 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hashomer Hatzair, NY: Articles, 471009 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Sam Katz), 471008 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Himno de Riego and Other Songs, undated; 498222 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Hispanic Volunteers (J. Fernandez Article), 471007 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hoover Institution: Bolloten Collection (Guide), 471006 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hospitals, 471005 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hospitals: Benissa, 471004 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hospitals: Cambrils, 471003 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Illinois Volunteers, 471002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Indian Volunteers, 471001 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, 471000 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - International Brigades: 59th Battalion, 470999 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - International Brigade Memorial Trust (UK), 470998 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - International Brigades: Battalion List, 470997 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - International Brigades: General, 470996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - International Brigades: Moscow Archive, Photograph Collection Guide, 470995 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - International Institut voor Sociale Gescheidenis (Amsterdam): CNT Photo Archive, 470994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - International Labor Defense of Spain, 470993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Support for Spanish Republic, 470992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - International Youth Commission, 470991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Irish and Irish-American Volunteers, 470990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Italian Intervention, 470989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Italian Volunteers, 470988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Italian-American Volunteers, 470987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Israel Association of Volunteers of the International Brigades in Spain (1936-39), 470986 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jaily News, 470985 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Jaily News" - No. 15 Page 2 (Box Shared Tamiment 044, Folder 4)
  - Jarama, 470984 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Jarama: Memorial at Moratea de Tajua, 470983 (Box 12, Folder 12)